<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eisuke Hirota</title>
    <link>https://ei5uke.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Eisuke Hirota</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 13:34:54 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ei5uke.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ai/Robots in Fiction ver. 8 -- Metal Gear Solid 2</title>
      <link>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/2025/mgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 13:34:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/2025/mgs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Metal Gear Solid&lt;/em&gt; series is a cult favorite for many reasons, but to give a sentence to sell you on the series, it&amp;rsquo;s an over-the-top serious anti-war story with tons of goofy boss fights and funny characters. While there&amp;rsquo;s tons of comedy and fun gameplay, the overall messages found within the games is profound and to me, I think &lt;em&gt;Metal Gear Solid 2&lt;/em&gt; is where its significance kickstarts. I&amp;rsquo;d like to explain the brilliance of this specific piece here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ai/Robots in Fiction ver. 7 -- CRYMACHINA</title>
      <link>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/2025/crymachina/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 13:34:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/2025/crymachina/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;preface&#34;&gt;Preface&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was in Japan during the winter break, visiting family like usual. I tend to go to BookOff to buy used goods (thrifting clothes mostly) and was in the game section when a certain piece caught my eye. The game&amp;rsquo;s package had beautiful art with its composition - surely it&amp;rsquo;s a well-known game I thought. To my surprise, this game isn&amp;rsquo;t very known and has a relatively low Metacritic score (I literally don&amp;rsquo;t trust any of these dog-ass video game critics especially IGN) and meh user ratings (I trust these reviews though). So, I just put it back in the aisle and went with my day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ai/Robots in Fiction ver. 6 -- Summer Wars</title>
      <link>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/2025/summerwars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 13:34:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/2025/summerwars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To my former labmate and friend &lt;a href=&#34;https://yoheihayamizu.github.io/yhayamizu/&#34;&gt;Yohei Hayamizu&lt;/a&gt;, Summer Wars was one of the more influential works that sparked his decision to enter robotics, AI, and in general, higher technology. And for 6-year-old me when I first watched it, I could not agree more. The breathtaking music, animation, and crazy breadth in terms of technology is just Hyminal to any tech junkie.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/HmjQrtJ.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Summer Wars Poster&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Summer Wars is at its core, a story that revolves around the setting of future Japan, and the integration of Oz, a digital world akin to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metaverse&#34;&gt;metaverse&lt;/a&gt;, in Japanese society. Oz is heavily engrained within every aspect of society - from mainly acting as a social media hub to a control unit for various physical “computerized” entities like fire hydrants and traffic signals (we’ll get back to this second point later). Everyone has their own customized characters that represent their identities, and Oz acts as a second society for people. Users can participate in various events, transactions, and games within this digital world, e.g., one of the protagonist’s allies, alias King Kazuma, is famous in Oz for being the number one hand-to-hand combat fighter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ai/Robots in Fiction ver. 5 -- 13 Sentinels</title>
      <link>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/2025/sentinels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 13:34:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/2025/sentinels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Get in the robot, Shinji” - Misato, &lt;em&gt;Neon Genesis Evangelion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This famous quote encompasses the unwillingness by Shinji to pilot the 01 Eva due to interpersonal depression and external expectations and duty set from society. Now, imagine this, but add 12 more characters who bare the responsibility to pilot mechs to protect humanity. This is the setup for the game 13 Sentinels: Aegis Rim developed by Vanillaware and released by Atlas. I already love Atlas (notably the Persona Games, Metaphor, and Catherine), so as I looked for other serious games to play on my switch, I stumbled upon this. And boy oh boy, this game is batshit insane.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ai/Robots in Fiction ver. 4 -- Doraemon and Dead Dead Demon&#39;s Dededededestruction</title>
      <link>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/2024/ddddd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 13:34:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/2024/ddddd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JqsPrYf5ZYM&#34;&gt;anime&lt;/a&gt; released, I thought it’d be great for me to introduce Dead Dead Demon’s Dededededestruction (DDDD) next. This is a manga made by esteemed author Inio Asano, famous for Solanin and his masterpiece, Oyasumi Punpun. This work is not as depressing as his other works (which is, in some sense, a good thing), but still conveys a great depth of existential dread so I’d highly recommend reading it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/odmGx9T.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;DDDD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ai/Robots in Fiction ver. 3 -- Ai: The Somnium Files</title>
      <link>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/2024/ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 13:34:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/2024/ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AI: The Somnium Files is a murder mystery game created by Kotaro Uchikoshi, known for the Zero Escape series (AMAZING STUFF). You play as Date, an amnesiac detective and aim to solve a potential revived serial killing in a futuristic society. While I can definitely talk all day about the entire plot and twists that happen throughout the game, I’ll just stick to the AI stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The entire core of AI in this game follows a single character, but before we get into that, I first want to give a little background, specifically, the title of the game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ai/Robots in Fiction ver. 2 -- Pluto</title>
      <link>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/2024/pluto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 13:34:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/2024/pluto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pluto follows a futuristic world in which technology is much advanced, to the point where robots exist in our every day lives. While this shows a great promise for science, Pluto also posits an important question: “What happens if robots gain consciousness?” Can humans and robots coexist in such a world, or will this feat cause one of the factions to drive the other into extinction?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/C7skCOf.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Pluto Volume 7 Cover.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ai/Robots in Fiction ver. 1 -- NieR</title>
      <link>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/2024/nier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 13:34:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/2024/nier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like entertainment, and a huge part of the reason I’m into math and cs and stuff is due to the fiction material I’ve ingested. Subsequently, I want to talk about all the fiction material that’s impacted my life and my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is because sci-fi brings up many points that ponder how the world will be impacted by new technology. I mean for one, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WarGames&#34;&gt;War Games&lt;/a&gt; hypothesized how a hacker could breach the military and launch a nuke - this fictional story persuaded the federal government to relook at the, then current, regulations regarding internet protocol.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>posts</title>
      <link>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/posts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This list compiles all posts to my blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ai/Robots in Fiction&lt;/em&gt; - I give my thoughts on sci-fi pieces that involve AI and robots, primarily through the mediums of games and manga. I try to remain spoiler free, but my arguments tend to require a lot of them, so you&amp;rsquo;ve been warned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2025&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../2025/mgs/&#34;&gt;Ai/Robots in Fiction ver. 8 – Metal Gear Solid 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../2025/crymachina/&#34;&gt;Ai/Robots in Fiction ver. 7 – CRYMACHINA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../2025/summerwars/&#34;&gt;Ai/Robots in Fiction ver. 6 – Summer Wars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../2025/sentinels/&#34;&gt;Ai/Robots in Fiction ver. 5 – 13 Sentinels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2024&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../2024/ddddd/&#34;&gt;Ai/Robots in Fiction ver. 4 – Doraemon and Dead Dead Demon’s Dededededestruction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../2024/ai/&#34;&gt;Ai/Robots in Fiction ver. 3 – Ai: The Somnium Files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../2024/pluto/&#34;&gt;Ai/Robots in Fiction ver. 2 – Pluto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../2024/nier/&#34;&gt;Ai/Robots in Fiction ver. 1 – NieR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>research bio</title>
      <link>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ei5uke.github.io/posts/me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://scholar.googleusercontent.com/citations?view_op=medium_photo&amp;amp;user=NBvMsAMAAAAJ&amp;amp;citpid=2&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hello, I’m Eisuke (英祐), currently an undergrad generally interested in robot learning. I’ve a keen interest in (inverse) Reinforcement Learning and commonsense reasoning. As of now, I’ve mainly worked in quadruped locomotion and manipulation, as well as preference-based rl. My long-term mission is to contribute to the development of robots to human-inhabited environments (such as in hospitals or the home) that collaborate with us, with reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SUNY Binghamton, BS in Computer Science (2021-2025)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Experience (institution and advisor):&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;MIT Lincoln Laboratory, TBD (2025-present)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;University of Southern California, Prof. Erdem Biyik (2024-2025)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SUNY Binghamton, Prof. Shiqi Zhang (2022-2024)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;New York University, Prof. Chen Feng (2022-2023)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
